hotels4u.com 2009-08-13

# Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy  
Hotels4u.com Limited’s Privacy Policy sets out what information we collect, how we collect it, and how we use it

INFORMATION ABOUT YOU 

Your Details    
Here we are referring to information like your name, contact details, travel preferences and special needs/disabilities/dietary requirements that you supply us or is supplied to us by a third party (e.g. a travel agent) including any information about any other person on your booking relating to the same (“your details”). Your details are collected when you request information from us, contact us (and when we contact you) or when you make a booking with us. You are responsible for ensuring that other members of your party are aware of the content of our Privacy Policy and agree to your acting on their behalf in all your dealings with us. We will update our records whenever we have the opportunity to keep your details up to date, accurate and complete.

Our Use of Your Details    
(1) To keep you informed of our services, including hotels, insurance & transfers, etc., we may disclose your details to our service providers (who could be located outside the UK/EEA). In order for you to travel overseas, it may be necessary to disclose your details for immigration, security and anti-terrorism purposes, or any other purposes which is deemed appropriate. Even when this information is not mandatory, we may exercise our discretion to assist where appropriate.   
(2) We may collect and use your details for the purposes set out in our registration with the Office of the Information Commissioner, and disclose the same to our “group companies” (some of whom are outside the UK/EEA) for business purposes. We may also disclose your details to companies who act as “data processors” on our behalf, or to our service providers, operating systems or business functions on our behalf, some of whom are outside the UK/EEA. These purposes include administration, providing services (and contacting you where necessary), customer care, improving our service, business management and operation, re-organisation/structuring/sale of our business (or our group companies), risk assessment, security and crime prevention/detection, research and analysis, marketing, monitoring, measuring and assessing customer purchasing preferences and trends, dispute resolution, credit checking and debt collection.   
(3) Some of your details (such as health or religion) may be considered “sensitive personal data” under the Data Protection Act 1998. We collect it to cater to your needs or act in your interest, and we are only prepared to accept sensitive personal data from you on the condition that we have your positive consent. By booking with us you also agree for your insurers, their agents and medical staff to disclose relevant information (which may contain sensitive personal data) to us in circumstances where we need to act in the interest of everyone in the group you are travelling with. For example, if your illness at resort is infectious we may need to make special arrangements for you and also ensure that you do not return with the group immediately.   
If you do not agree to Our Use of Your Details above, we cannot do business with you or accept your booking.

Direct Marketing Material  
(1) We may from time to time contact you with information on offers of goods and services, new products, forthcoming events or competitions. Please note that our websites will assume you to agree to e-communications when you make a booking. You will be given the opportunity on every e-communication we send you to indicate that you no longer wish to receive our direct marketing material.   
(2) You may indicate your preference regarding receiving third party direct marketing material.   
(3) If do not wish to receive such information or would like to change your preference, please refer to point (2) of “Your Rights” below. 

Your Rights    
(1) You have the right to ask in writing by completing our Data Subject Access Request form for a copy of the information we hold about you (for which we may charge a fee) and to correct any inaccuracies in your details.   
(2) You have the right to ask in writing not to receive direct marketing material about our products and services. If the following facilities are available, you can amend your previous preference on our website(s), using our “unsubscribe e-mail” or in literature which you subsequently return to us. Once properly notified by you, we will take steps to stop using your details in this way. 

Foreign Controls  
Outside the European Economic Area (EEA), note that controls on data protection in such countries may not be as strong as the legal requirements in this country. 

USE OF TOOLS/"COOKIES" AND LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES    
If our contact and dealing with you is via our website(s), we may use “cookies”. Cookies allow us to identify your computer but not you personally. You can set your web browser to refuse cookies. However, you may not be able to enjoy all the facilities or book via our website if you do so. We collect information relating to customer trends and patterns and use cookies and software tools to measure site usage and related information. If you are making a purchase, we may also use cookies to keep track of the transaction from one web page to another.

Our website(s) may contain links to other sites not controlled by us. We are not responsible for the actions, content or the privacy policies of those websites. It is your responsibility to check the status of these sites. 

MONITORING    
To ensure that we carry out your instructions accurately, to help improve our service and in the interest of security, we may monitor and/or record: (1) your telephone calls; (2) customer activities using CCTV recording equipment in and around our premises; and (3) customer transactions and activities on our website. All recordings are and shall remain our sole property. 

SECURITY STATEMENT    
We have taken all reasonable steps to have in place appropriate security measures to keep your details safe.

CHANGES TO THIS POLICY    
Any changes to this Policy will be either posted on our website, or made available on request.
